hey everyone welcome back to the stores
car automation playlist and today we are
going to discuss about another
interesting feature which is available
in the Tosca uh tool so we are going to
talk about uh how you can use the
recording feature to develop automated
test cases so until now we have been uh
basically scanning the modules of a
particular web application or desktop
application and then create a test case
from that module
but there is also a feature called
recorder okay through which you can
record all your actions which are
performing on a particular application
and Tosca will automatically create the
necessary modules and the test cases for
you so you don't need to uh do it every
time manually
obviously uh the preferred way is to
scan your own modules and prepare your
own structure but if you want to do a
quick round of
um
test on your application whether it is
feasible for you to work with Tosca then
you can use this particular way of
quickly recording all your actions on
your web application and then you can do
that visibility analysis of whether
Tosca is feasible for your web
application or not okay or even for
small applications where you need a
quick automation solution you can use
this recording feature okay
so talking about uh the recorder okay so
it is available on the home menu bar it
is the last option you can see here it's
called a recorder and automated test
case okay
now there are two options here one is
automated test case which you can create
you can also create a automated data
driven test cases okay so this will
basically also include a test sheet from
where you can drive your test case based
on the data provided okay
now let's look at some of the options
which are available in this recorder
menu okay
so first if you want to start off with
this recorder feature then either you
can select from these two options or you
can directly click on this okay and then
it will start loading the recorder as
you can see
okay so as you can see there is a
recorder in the background which is
coming up here and this is the recorder
menu okay so if the first option is to
show all the recorder settings then you
can create a image based test step okay
so we have already seen how you can do
uh image based Automation in Tosca and
the same you can do it here okay
um and then you can also switch to
verification mode in this particular
recorder okay
now there are other options uh here is
the pause button and here is the Stop
and Save button okay and here is the
recorder
option right
so I can pause this particular recording
okay and I can navigate between
different pages of my application
I can stop and save my recording once it
is finished I can switch to verification
mode okay uh using this uh tick sign and
you can also do a image based desktop
okay so if I click on this
um then I can just uh basically do a
image based control okay so you can see
here it will it is the same
functionality which we did from the
module section but you can do it here as
well okay
uh to cancel uh you just press escape
and it will go back to the previous mode
okay uh we can see the recorder settings
uh right here okay so here you can see
our Auto record Mouse over is off right
now you can keep the hints on uh you can
reuse existing modules okay
uh you can also
block some processes from recording uh
you can use this shortcuts uh to maybe
change the recording mode or record
Mouse over or refresh the recorder okay
so these are all the settings which are
available in the recorder
now how you can record basically so once
you click on the record option it will
start recording your screen okay
and it will record the whole screen as
you can see there are four corners uh
which are being displayed on Each corner
that is a red sign that means it is
recording okay
so let's go ahead and stop this recorder
now I just wanted to show you uh the
menu which is available with the
recorder but we'll go ahead and record a
particular uh flow from my application
and I will show you okay but as you can
see once you stop and save the recorder
it will create a folder and then it will
create all the uh modules which were
recorded and as well as the test cases
and if you use any verifications those
will also be captured okay so that will
be created a folder will be created in
your project as you can see here
okay with the modules and test cases
so that's how the recorder works so
let's go ahead and record a particular
scenario I'm going to use the demo
webshop from class centers to record a
particular end-to-end scenario and show
you how the test cases and modules are
created okay
so here let's click on automated test
case Okay so it will record it now let's
go to our website and here we are going
to click on login
and then it will type the email address
and the password okay and then click on
login
and then I will go to some item I will
add it to the cart
and then I will go to the cart
once this has been added let's try one
more time
Okay click on add to cart
and then go to the shopping cart
here I'm going to check out
and then I'm going to go through all the
steps mentioned in the checkout uh the
billing address shipping address uh
everything okay
so this is basically a end to end flow
of this particular application
so I'll go through all the steps and the
recorder will record it
okay
just click on continue
till I reach the final confirmation
okay so this is the final confirmation
page I will click on confirm
okay and you can see uh there is a hint
showing press Ctrl shift plus h to
record a mouse over event
or you can press F5 to refresh the
recorder or you can also press Ctrl
shift V to switch to verification mode
okay so if I press Ctrl shift v v here
okay
or I can go to the menu and I can
click on this right
and then I can just
okay so that once you click on any
particular control then it will be added
to the verification
right now I will go back or I will turn
off the verification mode and I will
click on continue
okay so and then I can maybe click on
logout so that's that's the complete
flow of this uh shopping website where
we have added a product to the cart and
we have checked out that product okay
so that's our complete flow and now I'm
going to uh stop and save this recording
and we'll see uh what has been recorded
so far okay
so as you can see a new folder has been
created uh and all the modules have been
automatically created okay with the
module attributes uh you can obviously
change all these naming conventions
because these are the default name
conventions which have been used by
Tosca and it's recommended if you are
using this in your test cases for a real
execution uh you should change all this
okay depending on what action you are
providing you can do this so as you can
see
um one of the examples is we are
clicking on the login button so the
value is X which means it is clicking on
this action mode is input right
um similarly again login it is going to
desktops and clicking on it
um and then add to cart
okay so uh whatever you have performed
whatever actions you performed on the
application it has been recorded uh and
it has been provided to you in the test
case based on the steps okay you can see
there is also a verification uh here uh
whenever I changed to uh the verify mode
and I clicked on that particular text it
is verifying whether this inner text is
the same which is displayed in the
application because once the order is
placed I want to verify whether this
order number was verified okay
so that verification step is also there
so you can do both you can record your
actions you can also put verifications
while you are recording your actions
okay
and then
um it is clicking on logout okay so
there might be some uh
repeated steps which you may need to
remove because maybe you I have clicked
um this three times and that's why there
are three verifications or two
verifications one of them I have to
remove okay I need to change few things
uh this order number is static right now
so maybe I need to verify I need to
modify this test case right so not
everything uh would be ready once you
record your test case you obviously need
to make some changes before you try to
run this again but at least uh you don't
need to uh go ahead and
um
basically scan each module separately
that will take a little longer yeah as
you can see here as we are interacting
with the application everything was
recorded for you okay it's not the
perfect way of doing it but it's the
quickest way uh if you compare it to the
other way where you scan each module and
then you build your own test case okay
so in some situations uh this method
could be useful this recorder feature
would be useful okay uh but in most
cases you will be scanning your own
modules and building your own test cases
okay
so that's how you can use the Tosca
recorder feature to automate your test
cases uh the modules and test cases will
be automatically created you can add
your own verifications uh you can also
do a image based test step uh maybe I'll
show it sometime later but if you're
trying to use this then this is the way
how you do it
so that's all for this particular video
uh I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today uh on Tosca so keep
watching for more videos which are
coming up pretty soon
um on trash and testoster
so until we meet again uh keep watching
our Channel and do subscribe uh to our
channel so that you get notified about
each and every video which we post on
our Channel